MICHELLE GARCIA

Houston, Texas **↑** 281-871-9547 ****

garcia_michelle@att.net ✓

<u>LinkedIn Profile</u> in

MichelleMGarcia.com



OBJECTIVE

Experienced bilingual teacher with 8 years of experience in elementary education. Seeking to use my analytical and collaborative skills in a Front-end developer role. I am a highly motivated self-taught developer with a passion for beautiful, semantic code.



EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

MARCH 2017 - PRESENT

- Taught myself HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and Bootstrap
- Produced two responsive websites for local small businesses using Bootstrap for one, and hand-coding the other
- Programmed a web application for students to increase math fact fluency
- Earned a Grow With Google/Udacity Nanodegree scholarship

Bilingual Teacher | Klein ISD & Aldine ISD

AUGUST 2014 - JULY 2015

AUGUST 2005 – JULY 2012

- Transitioned Spanish-speaking students to English-only instruction
- Collaborated with colleagues to plan targeted, rigorous instruction
- Increased the state test passing rate each year



EDUCATION

Master of Education | Texas A&M University

AUGUST 2005 - MAY 2007

Bachelor of Science | University of Missouri-Columbia

AUGUST 2001 - MAY 2005

Concentration: Elementary Education with a Minor degree in Spanish



SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- iQuery
- Bootstrap 4
- Responsive layouts